Mr. Tusharkumar Natavarlal Bhatt (New Ranip, Ahmedabad)

MSc Physics (Exp: 8 years and 6 months)

Mail: 1) bhatt.tushar563@gmail.com (preferred), 2) btushar639@gmail.com

Personal Website: https://tushar-tb2.github.io/swr/

**JOB PROFILE:** 

### **Long term Commitment:**

R&D (Space and /or Material Science), Instrumentation, Characterization (Materials), Data analysis (Any data), Teaching

### **Online Commitment:**

Data mining and analysis (any data), Online teaching (Maths, Science for Std 8 to Std 10 and Maths, Physics for Std 11 to Std 12), Proofreading (science, maths, physics), Translation (Gujarati, Hindi, English – SWAYAM - a Central Govt. Project)

Other Progressive Skills: Front-end developer, Back-end developer, Full-stack developer programs, Practising Mutual Fund for 4.0 years (Personal – Direct Investment – with proved 11-15% return)

### **Experiences:**

## 1) Khyati School of Engineering (Lecturer, Ahmedabad)

Jul 2018-Jun 2019

Job profile: Teaching, Practical, Projects, documentation and screening for instrument orders, regular academic duties

Achievements: 3D cam measure project awarded by RED HAT, California, USA

### 2) Jay Formulation Lab (Quality Control Chemist, Kerala GIDC, Ahmedabad)

Mar 2018 – Jul 2018

Job profile: Documentation

Skills improved: SOP, URS, STP, as per IP, BP, US protocols

### 3) Institute for Plasma Research (Junior Research Fellow, Gandhinagar)

Jan 2015 - Dec 2016

Job profile: R&D Material science, Characterization

<u>Skills improved</u>: Physical Vapor Deposition, Magnetron Sputtering, Characterization by FE HR-SEM (Hands on), Ion Beam Sputtering, AFM, FTIR, XRD, ICP MS, Contact Angle Measurements, Raman Spectroscopy <u>Publication</u>: https://doi.org/10.1063/1.4964312

# 4) Venus International College of Technology (Lecturer, Gandhinagar)

Aug 2010 – Oct 2014

Job profile: Teaching, Practical, Projects, documentation and screening for instrument orders, regular academic duties

Others: Online lectures delivered at BISAG, Gandhinagar for Engineering Physics

## 5) Sal Institute of Technology and Engineering Research (Lecturer, Ahmedabad)

Jun 2009 - Aug 2010

Job profile: Teaching, Practical, Projects, documentation and screening for instrument orders, regular academic duties

### **Educational qualifications:**

- 1) MSC Physics 60.44% -(Jun 2007 Oct 2009) HNGU, Patan, Gujarat, India
- 2) **BSC** Physics 70.66% (Jun 2004 Sep 2007) HNGU, Patan, Gujarat, India
- 3) XII Science 55.00% (Jun 2003 Apr 2004) GHSEB Gandhinagar, Gujarat, India
- 4) X All subjects 81.57% (Mar 2001) GSEB Vadodara, Gujarat, India

### **Proficiency:**

1) Language: Gujarati (Mother tongue), Hindi, English

2) **Computer:** MS office, Origin 8.5

#### **Personal information:**

BOD: 15<sup>th</sup> March, 1987 Birth Place: Kandivali (Mumbai) Passport: Yes

Height: 5'5" Weight: 58kg Blood Group: O+

